All right, Corporal. Nip back and tell Captain Knight
it's all clear up 'ere. And get 'em to get a shift on!
好了, 下士．摸回去告诉 Knight 队长这里没问题了．再让他们换个班
Righto, Staff.
好的, Staff
This looks familiar - it's around this corner.
这个地方看起来眼熟 - 应该就在这个角落
Oh no!
噢, 不！
Oh, we can't get to the TARDIS!
噢, 我们没法到 TARDIS 那里了
No, Victoria, I'm afraid we can't.
不能, Victoria, 恐怕不能了
What's happened to Chorley, then?
Chorley 怎么啦？
That's what I'm wondering. Did he reach the TARDIS
before the fungus, or... or did he not?
这也是我好奇的地方．他是在大网之前到达了 TARDIS 吗？或者他没有？
You mean to say, he could have got to the TARDIS
and already have taken off in it?
你的意思是说, 他可能已经到达了 TARDIS, 并且已经把它开走了？
I don't know...
我不知道
Hey, come back, Doctor!
嘿, 回来, 博士！
It's alright, Jamie, I'm not going to do anything silly. I...
没事的, Jamie, 我不会做任何傻事的
I just want to try and get a little bit for an analysis.
我只是想试着弄一点拿回去分析
Oh Jamie, stop him!
噢, Jamie, 拦住他！
It's alright, Victoria.
没事的, Victoria
Has anyone got a box?
谁有个盒子不？
I've got my tobacco tin.
我有一个香烟盒
Oh, splendid.
噢, 很棒
But then, it's got tobacco in it.
不过呢, 里面还有香烟呢
Never mind.
没关系
Eh!... Oh, alright. I only hope you think the sacrifice is worth it!
诶！...哦, 好吧．我只是期望你觉得我的牺牲是值得的
Hold the tin for me, would you, Evans?
帮我拿着这个铁盒, 行吗, Evans？
Gone and set it off! Come on, now!
Oh, it's horrible!
噢, 太可怕了
Go on, Doctor, get it out!
继续, 博士, 把它弄出来
Hold the tin underneath!
There we are - now back, everyone, quickly!
Hello, Staff. It's alright, it's just Staff Arnold!
你好, Staff．没事的．是 Staff Arnold
One of these days, Evans my lad,
you're going to creep up onto someone once too often!
Well, that's life, innit Staff?
嗯, 这就是生命, 对吧 Staff
Any luck at Holborn?
Holborn 怎样了？
No - fungus.
Same back there.
Right. I'll tell the Colonel. You lot had better
get back to HQ. We'll be along in a few minutes.
好, 我会汇报给上校．你们最好回到总部去．我们过几分钟也会回去
Come on, Jamie, I'll just show this bit of fungus to Travers.
快来, Jamie, 我要把这点真菌展示给 Travers
Right.
好嘞
Hey, look at this!
嘿, 看看这个
Good Lord! That's Yeti!
上帝！那是雪怪！
You don't think they may still be here?
你绝对它们已经不在这里了？
I hope not!
我期望不在了！
Oh, Doctor!
噢, 博士！
D'you reckon they have?
你觉得他们已经得手了吗？
Have what?
得手什么？
Taken him? Like she said?
fixme
Yes, I'm very much afraid they have./
But why? Why didn't they just kill him? Unless...
是的, 恐怕它们真的已经得手了．不顾为什么？它们为什么不直接杀了他？除非．．．
Yes?
什么？
Well, unless they had a use for him.
除非它们拿他另有用途
Ah, Doctor. What's this I hear about Travers?
啊, 博士, fixme
'Scuse me, sir, but I think you ought to come to the Ops Room.
对不起, 先生, 但恐怕你得到操作室来一趟
Why? What's happening?
为什么？怎么了？
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again!
那些真菌, 又在移动了！
It's like a spider's web, ain't it?
看起来像是蜘蛛网, 是不？
Yes. And we're the flies, alright, but... where is the spider?
是的, 而我们就是苍蝇．好吧, 不过...蜘蛛在哪儿？
Better give the others a hand, Corporal.
最好给其他人帮一下, 下士
Sir.
是！
Doctor. Been thinking about what you were saying earlier, /20.7
博士, 我在想你之前说的话
about someone here in HQ being responsible for all this. /25.1
你说是总部的某个人得为这些情况负责
Could it have been Travers?
有可能是 Travers 吗？
I doubt it.
我表示怀疑
Well, after all he has disappeared.
但是, 不管怎么说他已经消失了
Yes - so has Chorley. I'd say he was a much more likely suspect.
是的, Chorley 也消失了．要我说他更像有嫌疑
True.
的确
On the other hand, of course, whoever is in league
with the Intelligence could still be amongst us here.
另一方面来看, 不管谁是大智慧的同盟, 他都有可能还在我们中间
That's a fact of which I am uncomfortably aware./45.6
我也意思意识到了这个事实, 这一点让我很不安
But tell me, Doctor, this Intelligence - exactly what is it?
不过跟我说说, 博士, 这个大智慧到底是个什么东西
Well I wish I could give you a precise answer. /53.3
嗯, 我期望我能够给你一个确切的答案
Perhaps the best way to describe it is
a sort of formless, shapeless thing /58
也许最好的描述是, 它是一种无形无体的东西
floating about in space like a cloud of mist,
only... with a mind and will.
像一团云雾一样漂浮在太空中, 只有意识和意志
What's it after? What's it want?
它在追求什么？它想要什么？
I wish I knew. The only thing I know for sure
is that it brought me here.
我期望我知道．我唯一确切知道的就是, 它把我带到这里了
Brought you here?
把你带到这里？
Yes, been wondering how you got here.
是．我也好奇你是怎么到这里的
Yes, well I... I don't think there's any harm
in telling you now. I... /20.5
这个...我觉得现在告诉你们也没有什么问题, 我...
I have a craft, that travels in time and space.
我有一艘飞船, 可以穿越时间和空间
Oh, come now Doctor, you can't expect me to...
噢, 得了博士, 你不会指望我会...
This craft of yours, this time-space craft.
Could it get us out of here?
你的这个飞船, 时空飞船, 它能把我们带出这里吗？
Well, yes - but it's at Covent Garden!
嗯, 可以 - 但它现在在科文特花园
What does it look like?
它是什么样子的？
It's a police box.
是个警察亭
Oh really, Colonel, surely you're not...
噢, 真的吗, 上校, 你不会...
So - if we could rescue that craft, you could take us out?
这么说, 如果我们能弄回那个飞船, 你就能把我们带出去？
Yes, yes I could, but I have to stay here and finish Travers' work!
是的, 我可以．但我现在必须呆在这里, 完成 Travers 的工作
Ah, Doctor. Miss Travers is feeling alright now,
and would like to see you right away.
啊, 博士, Travers 小姐现在感觉没事了, 现在想马上见你
Very good, Jamie. Excuse me, gentlemen, please.
很好, Jamie．请原谅, 先生们
Yes.
好的
Well, I've heard some stories in my time, but that one really takes...
哈, 我听过不少故事, 那个故事还真是...
So you don't believe him?
看来你不相信他？
No, of course not, sir! The whole idea is screwy. A police box!
不, 当然不, 头儿！整个故事都很怪诞, 警察亭！
Well whether you think it foolish or not, we are going to rescue that craft.
好了, 不管你觉得它是不是傻, 我们都要去找那艘飞船
Oh, but sir! Our job...
噢, 但是头儿！我们的任务...
Captain Knight. The Army has failed to defeat this menace./15.2
Knight 队长, 在消除这个威胁上面, 军队已经失败了
Now the Doctor thinks he might succeed. Personally, I doubt it. /18.8
现在博士觉得他可能成功．个人来说，我也表示怀疑
But if we stay here, we're as good as dead. /20.8
但如果我们待在这里, 我们还是死翘翘
Therefore I do not intend leaving any escape route unexplored,
however... screwy you may think it.
所以我不会可能还有一条路而不去尝试, 不过这条路你觉得如何怪诞
Oh, surely Colonel...
噢, 好吧上校
Let's get on with it, shall we, Knight?
我们开动吧, 行不, Knight？
Sir.
是！
But... but there must be a chance! If the Doctor says...
但是...这里肯定还有可能的！如果博士说...
No, the soldiers could comb these tunnels
for a fortnight and still never find him. /42.2
不, 士兵们在隧道里来回排查两周, 也不一定能找到他
I'm afraid your father's been taken by the Intelligence. /45.5
我担心你的父亲已经被大智慧给抓走了
The only way that we can save him
is by finding the central control source.
我们能救他的唯一途径是找到中心控制源
Aye, if he's anywhere, that's where he'll be.
是, 如果他在什么地方, fixme
But why? Why him? Why not me, or one of the soldiers, or...
但是为什么？为什么是他, 而不是我, 也不是其他哪个士兵, 抑或...
Yes, I know. Tell me, what was your father working on /33.2
是的, 我知道．告诉我, 你父亲之前在研究什么？
just before the Yeti broke in, Anne?
在雪怪出现之前, Anne?
Um... oh, we were ready to test the sphere with the control unit,/11.0
嗯...哦, 我们已经准备好要用控制器来测试球体了
but I don't see what this has to do with anything, Doctor.
但我看不出来这跟这些有什么关系, 博士
But don't you? If he was near to success...
看不出吗？如果他快要成功了...
That's why they took him!
那就是它们抓走他的原因
Well, it's a possibility, isn't it? /21.3
对，这是有可能的，是不？
Now Anne, do you feel strong enough to come back to the laboratory?
现在，Anne，你觉得你恢复得怎样了，可以回到实验室吗？
Yes, yes of course.
可以，当然可以
Anything we can do?
我们能做点什么？
No, no, you just take it easy, Jamie.
不，不用，你就休息一下吧，Jamie
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I've been thinking about what the Doctor said. /33.6
我在想博士所说的是
Anything we do, the Intelligence always knows!
不管我们做什么，大智慧总是自知道！
Aye, but I wouldn't let it worry you. The Doctor will soon find a way out.
是，不过我不会让这个事烦你。博士很快会找到解决办法得到
I wish I could believe that.
真期望我能接受这个
Oh yes. Yes, this seems to be in order, Anne.
哦是的，是的，这似乎是正常的，Anne
My father didn't want it put together until this was in proper order.
我父亲不想在一切就绪之前不想把组合拼起来
Very wise. Let's have a look at this...
很明智。我们来看看这个
Oh yes, yes... My word, this is a splendid piece of work, Anne.
啊是，是的...我得说，这是一件了不起的作品，Anne
Thank you.
谢谢你
Yes, this should control the sphere, alright, but /06.3
是的，这可以操纵球体，很好
would it override the commands issued by the Intelligence, I wonder?
但它能否压制大智慧发出的命令呢，我想知道
No. No, I'm afraid it won't. I just didn't have the time.
Do you think we can do it.
不，恐怕不能。我还没有时间来弄。你觉得我们可以搞定吗？
Oh, we can do it, if you've got the right bits and pieces.
哦，我们可以搞。只要你有正确的零配件
Hope I'm not disturbing, Doctor, but Staff asked me to give you this.
期望我没打扰你，博士。不过 Staff 让我把这个交给你
Where'd you get this?
你从哪儿得到这个的？
On the floor, by that young lad Weams, it was.
地上, Weams 那个年轻小伙子捡到的
But this is what brought the Yeti to the explosives store!
但就是这个东西把雪怪引到炸药储藏室的
It's obviously been reprogrammed as a homing device,
and you've given it to me!
很显然它被改成了一个发出归巢信号的装置, 而你居然把它给了我！
Here! You don't think I had anything to do with these Yeti, do you?
嘿, 你不是认为我跟这些雪怪有什么关系吧, 是吗？
Doctor! The other models - they've gone!
博士！其它的模型呢, 不见了！
Well don't look at me!
I didn't want to come down here in the first place
别看我啊！我一开始就不想下到这里来
I shouldn't be down here at all, really. Driver, I am, see.
我根本就完全不该到这里来, 真的, 我只是个司机, 对不
You'd better have this, before you say I've nicked it.
你最好拿走这个, 免得你又说我藏匿了它
Thank you.
谢谢你
And I'll have the tin back, when you've finished with it.
而且等你用完了, 我还要把铁盒拿回来的
Don't look so unhappy - we're all under suspicion,
you know, including me.
别那么不高兴 - 我们所有人都有嫌疑, 你知道的, 包括我
Hmm!
哼！
What's in the tin, Doctor?
铁盒里面有什么, 博士？
It's the fungus from the tunnel. I thought if
we examined it, it might give us a clue.
是在隧道里面采集的真菌, 我想如果我们研究一下它的话, 也许会有点线索
I must get this dismantled. It's like holding a time bomb.
我得把这个破解掉, 感觉像拿着一颗定时炸弹似的
So my party will get above ground and approach
Covent Garden by Neal Street. Is that clear?
我的人会到地面上去, 从尼尔街往科文特花园站靠拢, 清楚了吗？
Now Staff here will be taking the trolley through the tunnel,
Staff 现在就把推车从这里弄到隧道里面去
and will arrive, we hope, at the same time as we do.
You picked your two men, Staff?
跟我们到达的时间应该一样, 我期望．你选两个你的人带上, Staff？
Yes, sir. Lane and Evans.
是, 头儿, 就 Lane 和 Evans 吧
Right. Now as soon as we get there,
we shall be looking for a police box.
好．等我们一到那里, 就开始寻找一个警察亭
A police box, sir?
一个警察亭吗, 头儿？
Yes, a police box. Now I want that box either out of the station/
or onto the trolley as quickly as possible. Is that understood?
是的, 一个警察亭．现在我想要的是尽快将它弄出站外或者弄到推车上, 清楚了吗？
Yes, sir.
是, 长官
Right. Any questions?
好, 还有问题吗？
Yes, sir, this, um... police box. Is it important?
有, 长官．这个, 嗯... 警察亭, 它重要吗？
Corporal Blake, we'd hardly be going to this trouble if it weren't.
Blake 下士, 如果它不重要我们就不用费这个事了
Who's going to look after the civilians, sir?
谁来照看这几个平民, 长官？
I'd like you to stay behind and look after them, Captain Knight.
我期望你留下来照看他们, Knight 队长
The Doctor's got work to do. Right gentlemen, time to go.
博士还有工作要完成．好了先生们, 该行动了
- Ah, Doctor.   - Oh Jamie, what is it?
- 啊，博士   - 哦，Jamie，什么事
The Colonel says to tell you he's on his way.
上校让我告诉你他们已经出发了
On his way where?
出发去哪儿？
To rescue the TARDIS!
去寻回 TARDIS！
He's wasting his time.
他是在浪费时间
Well that's what I told him. And I think that man Chorley must be behind...
我也是这么跟他说的。而且我觉得那个 Chorley 应该在背后...
Now look! Get behind me, both of you, and keep clear. Here we go...
来看！到我后面去，你俩都是，别乱动。开始了
No!
不！
What is it, Doctor?
怎么了，博士？
The tin's empty!... Evans!
铁盒是空的！... Evans！
Course, really I shouldn't be doing this, you know, Staff. /19.2
当然，我真不该这么干，知道吗，Staff
Not officially on the strength down here, see. /21.2
What I am really is a driver, you see...
但实际上我只是个司机，你看...
Don't try to come the old soldier with me, lad!
别跟我玩老兵油子那一套，小子！
Who, me?
谁，我吗？
Yes, you! And when we get in the tunnels, don't you try to skive off,
是，你！等我们进了隧道，你别想溜走
'cos if you do I'll have you for breakfast. D'you understand?
如果你要溜，我会把你当早餐吃了，明白吗？
Trolley's ready, Staff.
推车准备好了，Staff
Right, come on!
好，快点！
So far, so good. If we don't see any Yeti,
we should make Covent Garden in about ten minutes. Come on!
目前一切还好。如果没有碰到雪怪，我们应该能在10分钟左右到达科文特花园站。快点
Captain, they've gone, and Evans with them, I think.
I can't find him anywhere.
队长，他们不见了，我估计 Evans 也跟他们在一起。我哪儿也找不到他
Yes, well we'd better question Evans carefully when he gets back.
好，等 Evans 回来我们得仔细盘问他
Aye, if he gets back.
是，如果他回得来
It's a funny business, Doctor, that fungus disappearing.
这就奇怪了，博士，真菌不见了
Yes, yes I know... Don't worry about that just at the moment.
是的，我知道...这会儿先别操心那个
I've been working on this control box with Miss Travers.
我跟 Travers 小姐在研究这个控制盒
There's a few more things I need - transistors, circuits...
我还需要一些东西，晶体管，电路...
Aren't there any in Stores?
储藏室里面没有吗？
No, not of the right type.
没，没有合适的型号
Well in that case, Doctor, I can't help you.
那这种情况下，博士，我就帮不了你了
Well - I was wondering... if I could go up to street level...
是这样，我在想，能不能上去到街上...
The mist! Or the Yeti!
有雾瘴，还有雪怪！
There's no mist directly above us here - we'd have to risk the Yeti.
在我们的正上方没有雾瘴，雪怪的险我们得冒承担
No. No, I'm afraid that's out.
不, 不行, 我觉得这不行
It's terribly important. Please!
这事非常重要, 求你了！
It'll only take five minutes.
大约只需要五分钟
Alright. I'll get my gear.
好吧, 我去拿我的工具
Well done, Travers!
干得好, Travers!
The Colonel will be through there at Covent Garden
in a few minutes, right?
上校会fixme在几分钟内到达科文特花园, 对吧？
Do you think they'll be able to load the police box on here, Staff?
你觉得他们会将警察亭送到这里来吗, Staff?
Well, if we can get this thing through the fungus stuff -/53.7
唔 - 就看我们能否把这个东西穿过真菌网了
there's not much of a gradient in this section of the tunnel. /57.7
隧道里面这一片没有多大坡度fixme
Right, I want one volunteer.
行, 我需要一个志愿者
Volunteer? That's a dirty word, that is. Not me!
志愿者？ 这词真不好听．我可不干！
Lane?
What for, Staff?
做什么, Staff?
Well, if this thing wants some help going through
to Covent Garden, I'm going through with it...
这样, 如果这个东西需要点帮助才能穿过去到达科文特花园, 我就得自己来...
Into that stuff?
进那里面去吗？
Have we got those respirators?
我们带了防毒面具了吗？
Well yeah, here.
哦, 是的, 这里
I reckon we should be all right in these.
我估计我们戴着这个应该就没事了
Oh all right, Lane lad. I'll go by meself.
哦, 没事, Lane, 我打算自己过去
No, 'ang on a sec, Staff. That trolley's heavy,
it'll take two of us to shift it.
不, 等一下, Staff．推车很重, 需要我们两个人才能推动
Good lad. Come on.
好小伙, 来吧
You're potty, the pair of you!
你们不行的, 你们俩！
Shut up, will you! Do as you're told.
闭嘴, 行吗！按吩咐的做！
Play that rope out as we go;
any sign of trouble whip us out sharpish. Right?
我们往前走的时候拉住那个绳子, 一有问题就把我们死命往外拉, 行吗？
Well, it's your neck.
fixme
OK.
好
Alright then...
好了
Staff? Staff Arnold?...
Look, sir!
看, 头儿！
In Here! Quick!
进来, 快！
Come on, through the gate!
快点, 穿过门去！
I'm going to find a way out. Split up!
我打算找一条路出去, 分开吧！
Yetis - three of them, sir!
雪怪 - 它们有三个, 头儿！
Grenades!
手雷！
Right, fire!
好, 开火！
Sir, they're smashing down the gate!
头儿, 他们要把门撞倒了！
We can't hold 'em, sir!
我们挡不住它们了, 头儿！
Over the top, all of you!
到上面去, 都上去！
Grenades!
手雷！
Through the yard, come on!
穿过院子, 快点！
Right, bazooka here to cover the others.
好, 用火箭炮掩护其他人
Dawson! Langley!
Make for the warehouse!... Murphy!
冲到仓库去！...Murphy！
There it is again, Doctor!
fixme
Just one more thing.
还有一件事
For heaven's sake, hurry up!
看在上帝的份上, 赶快！
I just need one more component. I'll look through here.
我就还需要一个零件, 我要去这里找找
Doctor! Doctor, look out!
博士！博士, 小心！
No! No!
不, 不！
And this was in his pocket, you say?
这之前在他口袋里吗, 你说？
How did he get it? You said it was stolen.
他是怎么拿到的？你说过它被偷了
You can't think that he...
你不是觉得他...
No no no, he didn't steal it. The person who did planted it on him.
不, 不, 不是他偷的．偷的人放到他身上的
Hmm!
嗯！
Eh, don't you try and pin this on me, boyo!/
Strikes me, anything goes wrong around here and I'm always the one to get the blame.
嗯, 你别试图把这是栽到我头上,fixme
这里一有什么事情部队, 我总是背锅的那一个
Alright, alright, let's keep our temper, shall we?
The point is, two of these were missing. Now where's the other one?
好啦, 好啦, 我们都控制一下脾气, 好吗？
问题的关键是, 之前就有两个不见了, 还有一个在哪儿？
There. That one shouldn't bother us any more. /30.5
那儿．fixme
Now then, come along, Anne, let's get down to work.
Where did I put those bits and pieces?
现在, 过来, Anne, 我们聚焦工作．我把那些零件放哪儿了？
I wish I knew who put it in the Captain's pocket.
我期望我知道是谁把他放到队长的口袋里了
Well it must have been Chorley.
嗯, 肯定是 Chorley
Well look, he left ages ago.
但你看, 他早就离开了
It doesn't matter. He could still...
这无关紧要, 他仍然可以...
Colonel!
上校！
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
What's happened?
怎么了？
Colonel, what happened?
上校, 发生什么了？
Gone.
没了
Not all of them?
不是所有人吧？
All of them?
所有n热？
I said so, didn't I? All of them. Evans, what about your party?
我说过了, 是不？所有人．Evans, 你那边怎么样？
Arnold?
Gone, sir.
也没, 头儿
Captain Knight, too.
Knight 队长也是
Knight! Hopeless.
Knight! 没希望了
Can't fight them - it seems... indestructible. Can't fight them!
斗不过他们 - 看起来它是...刀枪不入的, 没法跟它们打！
You were right, Doctor, when you said they were...
formless, shapeless... you were right.
你是对的, 博士．你说过它们是...无形无体的...你说的是对的
Listen... listen, everyone! It's the other Yeti model!
It's here! It's somewhere in this room!
听...听, 所有人！是另外一个雪怪模型！在这里, 在这个房间里某个地方！
That noise, I've been hearing it on and off all day...
那个声音, 我一整天都时不时听见...
Your pockets!
你的口袋！
What?
什么？
Open your pockets, Colonel! Quickly, quickly, come on!
打开你的口袋, 上校！快, 快, 快点！
How... how...
怎么...怎么...
They bring the Yeti!
它们把雪怪引来了！